Hi everybody and welcome back to the channel.
Today I'm just going to stop the light jiggling
around, today we are going to look at No Churn
ice cream, yeah said I wouldn't do no churn,
here I am doing a no churn so let's just
get on and talk about the science behind it.
So this channel is all about ice cream,
this channel is about making the best ice
cream that you can make with your ice cream
machine machine. I don't do no churn recipes
for a reason they're everywhere on the internet
they're all [__] awful, regardless of opinion,
let's look at what goes into no churn and ice
cream. So a basic no Churn ice cream consists
of heavy cream or whipping cream depending on
where you're from and sweetened condensed milk.
Some people call it condensed milk I know this
is condensed milk certain parts of the US they
call it sweet and condensed milk and in some parts
of the world it's called evaporated milk which is
a whole different product unto itself so you know
anyway just to confirm condensed milk is the high
sugar reduced milk product okay not evaporated
milk which has basically no sugar in it you must
have the sugar in this product otherwise it won't
work so with that made clear why do people like
no CH ice cream well obviously not everyone has
an ice cream machine that's the simple fact of it
and some ice cream machines are expensive some are
dirt cheap you know you can get one for 30 bucks
you you can I remember buying one very early on
in the channel back in the UK I think I paid 15
15 GBP for that which is like $20 us anyway if you
don't want to buy one of those and you don't make
enough ice cream you don't want to eat enough ice
cream to Warrant a machine that's where no churn
comes in but here on Polar Ice Cream we talk about
the science behind ice cream as well and really
good ice cream has the right balance of fat and
sugar and the right amount of air inclusion and
the right size ice crystals the size of the Ice
Crystal determines the mouth fill if you think ice
cream is really creamy then it's got very small
ice crystals if it's really icy speaks for itself
sugar is ultra important in ice cream and this
also accounts for sugar substitutes whichever
one you choose to use they're very very important
in ice cream because those are what reduce the
freezing point of your mixture without the sugar
you'll end up with a solid block of ice instead
of ice cream okay I went online and found one
of the UK version no churn recipes that I tried
before moving over to Canada and and it had 270
G of double cream which is 50% fat in the UK oh
it's beautiful stuff um 110 GS of whole milk 100
g of sugar and 2 and 1 half gr of espresso powder
like instant espresso powder I don't think
you can get that over here it was [__] now
29% fat this equates to that little mixture
I just told you accounts for 29% fat 42% milk
Sol is non fat 20.8% % sugar 54.3 total solids I
mean if you put that in an ice cream calculator
you're going to be all over the place okay now we
can't do a lot about that with no chowing and ice
cream you whip air into the cream you mix the
ingredients together you put it in the freezer
we're going to do Cookie Monster no chain ice
cream but I'm not going to do two different types
of cookie I'm going to do one type of cookie and
cookie dough chunks so what are we going to need
for our Cookie Monster no Churn ice cream we are
going to need 400 G of condensed milk 400 G of
whipping cream at 33% that is a 10 oz can of
condensed milk and 1 to 3/4 cups of whipping
cream plus we're going to use vanilla extract this
is homemade blue food coloring and Oreo cookies
and and I'm going to use cookie dough that I've
made before if you want to know how I make this
let me know in the comments and I'll do a whole
video on how to make cookie dough so let's get
started super easy if you don't have
an ice cream machine I mean they're
very cheap on Amazon you can get them for
less than $20 you know it doesn't have to
be 10 G short close enough it doesn't have to be
the best ice cream machine in
the world way just has to be
functional you must get depending on where you
live in the world you must get the condensed
milk with very high sugar content that sugar
is important if you don't have the sugar in
your milk product and in this instance obviously
as a o churn it's going to be condensed milk you
will be left with a solid block of ice and we do
not want that so there we go cream and condensed
milk nice and going to stir that up and then
just whisk it whisk it for 5 minutes until it
starts to incorporate some air 5 minutes later
some people whip the cream first others don't
I find you get a better texture by whipping
all of it together if you got a machine use
that we've increased our volume by about 15
to 20% I can't get it any more than that now
we are going to put in our blue food coloring
we want it to be quite bright this is neon gel
I would recommend a gel based food coloring
rather than a liquid one there we go look ice
cream is vanilla flavored so in goes our vanilla
extract two teaspoons some something around 10
G Oreos standard Oreos there we go
right we need something to put it
in we are going to need I'm not even going to
go mad with measuring stuff just going to break
the
Oreos in there we go let's
get the Whisk out get out of
there one for
me Oreos much better over here this is
molted cookie dough now I did a video
probably two years ago now that was salted
melted chocolate chip cookie dough
salt and straw incredibly good ice
cream the recipe for the
cookie dough is actually in
there why am I pissing around just throw it all
in throw it all in stir it
together and into the tub it
goes LD on in the freezer it goes I will come back
probably tomorrow we'll dig this one out
of the freezer scoop it and see how it t
out next day let's get some of this no
churn Cookie Monster ice cream dished
up there we go I said I wouldn't do no churn
recipes but so many people have asked for them and
they've asked for them for a specific reason is
that they're very different on the internet some
recipes you find say this some recipes say that
now there is actually a scientific calculation
as to what you need fat and sugar percentage wise
for a good no churn recipe and that is somewhere
around 20 to 23% fat and 20 to 23% Sugar that is
what you need for a noch recipe to be a scoopable
b tasty and C have some reasonable texture it's
never going to be the same as a as a churned ice
cream because it's just it's an impossible task
but you're going to get reasonably close like I
said if you don't have an ice cream machine you
don't want an ice cream machine but you do want
to make your own ice cream you can use this base
recipe for any no churn out there just change
the food coloring take it out use an extract
to flavor do some inclusions so your add-ins
your cookies your cookie dough all that kind of
stuff you can really kind of start to change this
up when you look online at other no Chim recipes
there are some that have 15% fat 10% sugar they'd
be solid as a rock they would literally be a
block of ice if you made that then there are
some there's a commercial one back in the UK that
had 28% sugar and 20% fat 28% sugar I don't even
know how that froze you know it the chances are
they had a blast chiller that's the only real way
to actually get that kind of ice cream frozen but
but then once you start taking it out it's going
to defrost really really quickly until the point
where you put it in your home freezer and you try
and make it at home it just it won't it it won't
freeze or if it does it will be like a milkshake
rather than ice cream so if you're one of the new
subscribers and you want to see more no churn I I
will make more no Churn ice creams and explain the
difference but let's just eat it color great but
way texture wise it's not too bad you know it's
pretty smooth uh it's got a a nice vanilla kind
of taste to it the Oreos are perfect the cookie
dough is inspired everyone else just uses a plain
chocolate chip cookie along with your Oreos
you're more than welcome to do that take it up
a notch and make some cookie dough I'll put the
recipe in the description below but this recipe
actually is one of salt and straws and I will
link I'll put a link actually just up here um
that points to that video cuz it's an excellent
excellent ice cream the biggest downside to no
churn is the flavor of the condensed milk that
muddies the water for all the other flavors that
you use okay so condensed milk has a very strong
flavor how no churn works the high fat the fat
in in ice cream stops the ice crystals enlarging
as it's freezing the sugar reduces the freezing
point of the ice cream and the milk solids
nonfat in an ice cream recipe that's like your
protein and that helps with the overrun if you're
churning your ice cream in a machine or with your
whipping uh if if you're doing a no churn this is
actually pretty decent so science-wise there is a
place for no Churn it is nice and easy you don't
need anything special I hope you have enjoyed my
first nice and simple no churn Cookie Monster
ice cream let me know if you want to see some
more and we'll start branching out on some
other flavors you can get quite complicated
even with no churn so let me know if that's
something you want to see anyway less rambling
more cookies thanks for watching don't forget
to like And subscribe I'll see you next time
y